A comedy thriller about four men, a wedding and everybody's funeral.
Best Men is a comedy, romance film directed by Tamra Davis.
Four tuxedo clad men show up at a penitentiary to meet a friend who has just been released after
three years in prison and is going straight from the jail to marry his girlfriend.
En route to the wedding, one of the men asks to
stop by a bank to pick up some cash.
As it turns out, he is a wanted bank robber who uses Shakespeare passages
during his robberies and thus has become known as "Hamlet".
Soon all five men are caught up in the bank and involved in the
robbery as they end up in a hostage situation.
The hostage negotiator shows up who turns out to be Hamlet's father.
Buzz, played by Dean Cain.
Hope, played by Drew Barrymore.
Jesse, played by Luke Wilson.
Taddy, played by Andy Dick.
Billy, played by Sean Patrick Flanery.
Sol, played by Mitchell Whitfield.
Men in Black (abbreviated as MIB) is a 1997 American science fiction action comedy film directed by Barry Sonnenfeld,
based on a script by Ed Solomon, that adapts the Marvel Comics series The Men in Black by Lowell Cunningham.
Tommy Lee Jones and Will Smith respectively star as Agent K and Agent J, who investigate a series of
seemingly unrelated criminal incidents related to the extraterrestrials who live in secret on Earth.
Linda Fiorentino, Vincent D'Onofrio, and Rip Torn
also appear in supporting roles.
Development for the film began in 1992, after producers Walter F.
Parkes and Laurie MacDonald optioned the rights to the comic book series.
Solomon was soon hired to write the screenplay; Sonnenfeld was the preferred directorial choice, which resulted in
delays due to his commitments to other film projects and a failure to secure any alternative directors.
Principal photography began in March 1996 and lasted until that June,
with filming primarily taking place in New York City.
The film's visual effects were helmed by Industrial Light & Magic.
The film's soundtrack contains the theme song of the same name, performed
by Smith, as well as the score, composed by Danny Elfman.
Men in Black premiered at Pacific's Cinerama Dome in Hollywood on June 25, 1997, and was theatrically released
in the United States on July 2 by Sony Pictures Releasing through the Columbia Pictures label.
It received critical acclaim for its screenplay, humour, action sequences,
and the performances and chemistry between Jones and Smith.
The film was a box-office success, grossing more than $589.4 million worldwide and becoming the
third-highest-grossing film of 1997 as well as the ninth-highest-grossing film of the decade.
It won for Best Makeup and was also nominated for Best Art Direction and Best
Original Score at the 70th Academy Awards, among numerous other accolades.
A sequel was released in 2002, a third film was released in 2012, and a
stand-alone sequel was released in 2019, with Jones and Smith absent.
The film explores themes of release from prison, on the run,
wedding, woman director, bank robbery attempt.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.